The pact! The pact!
The pact!
No!
Morning, my Lord. Sorry to disturb you.
Who are you?
- Where's the Sheriff?
- I was about to ask the same question.
- Get out!
- Uh-uh-uh.
You hurt me, hurt Prince John.
I'm his special envoy.
Well, I've never seen you before.
That's because I arrive at dawn,
every other Thursday,
share a glass of wine with the Sheriff,
he stamps his seal here,
I take it to Prince John and the Prince
knows that all is well in the provinces.
But today...
all is not well, is it?
No Sheriff, no stamp.
And of course, you have no idea
what's happened to him.
- No.
- Well, then I suggest you find out.
You know the deal:
Anything happens to the Sheriff,
Prince John sends an army
to raze Nottingham to the ground.
- We don't know if anything's happened to him.
- Yeah, but he's not here!
That's all I need to know.
The troops will be here by sunset.
I've already sent the signal.
Nottingham is about to be flattened.
Agh! Ahh...
I've been watching you.
- You've been sleepwalking.
- What?
- Nice silk.
- I am the Sheriff of Nottingham.
I do not sleepwalk
and you will take me to Nottingham.
Maybe we should start again.
What a pretty mouth you've got.
Agh! Agh!
Agh!
And so... to Nottingham.
Ah! Ah...
Allan?
Where are you?
Organize the guard.
The Sheriff's missing.
Search every inch of the castle.
- Find him.
- Missing?
Find him!
Ah! I want the sun and I want it now!
Well, you can't always get what you want,
can you?
- This stable lass saw him go in the night.
- Go? Where?
Go on.
He went out on his horse. He was... mumbling.
- Mumbling?
- Just tell him what you told me.
He said, "Open the gate. "
And what did you do?
I opened the gate.
He was in his nightclothes, sir.
Comb the whole town, then get out
to all the villages. Just find him!
Well, I see
our kitchen is taking good care of you.
Good food's wasted on me,
but I can smell a rat.
What have you done to the Sheriff?
Sir Jasper, nothing has been done with him.
In fact, he was seen riding out of
the castle last night alive and well.
- We have a witness.
- I don't want a witness.
I want the Sheriff.
Now, what's for pudding?
Your patch? Don't be so ridiculous!
This is the King's forest.
We're working this patch, now clear off!
Work? You've never done a day's work
in your life!
Find your own sucker,
'cause Robin Hood's ours!
Robin Hood? Robin Hood comes here?
Like you don't know it's a drop point.
Now go on!
- Sling your hook!
- Very well.
Drop point? Off I shall sling.
Oh, this is good. This is very good.
Ow!
Right. He's not been seen in Locksley,
Nettlestone or Clun,
but there's reports of troop movements
on the North Road.
No!
- I heard about the Sheriff. Any news?
- Nothing.
What do you think?
If he hadn't left on his own accord,
I'd think this was Hood's work.
No. Hood knows the arrangement
between the Sheriff and Prince John.
He wouldn't let Nottingham be destroyed.
On this occasion,
I don't think Hood is the problem,
but he might be the solution.
How?
Well, Robin knows Nottingham and the forest
better than any man alive.
- If the Sheriff is out there...
- Hood won't help us.
- Well, have you asked him?
- We do not deal with outlaws.
This could be our only hope.
If I could get a message to him,
if I could bring him here to the...
To the castle.
You could bring Hood here
to the castle?
I think so.
He will not want Nottingham razed
to the ground, same as you.
Very well. Do it.
A good morning's work, lads. Well done.
Ahem, ahem, ahem.
What have you got there, John?
It lays golden eggs.
And tomorrow, there's a consignment
of magic beans coming in.
- John, I think we need to have a little...
- Oh, give me strength!
This is the booty, here!
This is for the kitchen.
Oh, could have done with some magic beans!
Well, I'm glad to see someone's laughing.
I'm on my own! Honest!
What do you want?
Marian said to show this
and you'd know I'm telling the truth.
All right?
She needs your help. Just for today,
you've got safe passage into the castle.
You don't expect us to believe that?
- Why?
- They've lost the Sheriff.
If we don't find him today,
an army is coming to destroy Nottingham.
We're leaving. Now.
We drop everything on the say-so of
a traitor to go and help our enemy?
John, I gave Marian this ring.
She wouldn't lie to me.
Come on.
Put it down!
Wait there.
Open the gates!
This is weird, I don't like it.
Can't we just sneak in anyway?
- After this, we go back, we help the poor?
- Yes, John.
There are people waiting. We have
four drop-offs today. They're relying on us.
All right.
Take these, Much.
Well!
You're a bigger man than I thought, Gisborne,
asking your enemy for help in a time of crisis.
It's your crisis as well, Hood.
You know what Prince John will do
if anything happens to the Sheriff.
- Have you searched the castle?
- Of course we have.
He was seen leaving last night,
on horseback... in his nightclothes.
Shock troops will be here by sundown.
Nottingham and everything in it
will be destroyed.
If anyone can find him, it's you.
You have people everywhere.
Go on then. Ask.
- What?
- Ask me for my help.
- Robin...
- Him.
We're wasting our time.
- Will you help us find the Sheriff?
- Of course I will.
Why else do you think I came?
Shoes... My kingdom for some shoes...
Ahh.
Oh, a change of clothes.
My man!
My ah! My... my dear fellow...
You, er... you do realize that those clothes
are worth at least 30 pounds?
Yeah, sure, and I'm the
Sheriff of Nottingham.
Ah-ha-ha... He-he-he.
- So?
- We have to find him.
- You and I will track him.
- Take one. Take one.
Will, I want you to wait in the town,
search every street, ask around.
Djaq, John... John!
Every day, more beggars.
- John, you need to focus.
- Are we making any difference?
- There.
- Robin, you can't just throw money at them!
Today we're trying to save everybody's life!
The Sheriff may be in the forest.
I want you and Djaq to go there.
Check all the regular drop points.
Somebody may have seen something.
Will?
I don't know how today will end, but whatever
happens, you need to look after Marian.
- Of course.
- Will, I'm relying on you.
She has to live, even if no-one else does.
- You do know Hood robs from the rich...
- We told you to clear off!
...to give to the poor, huh?
- What do you think we're doing here?
- Living off scraps, my dear.
Think about it. He robs from the rich.
He must have a huge stash somewhere.
And what does he give you?
A handful of scraps?
Don't talk rubbish.
If you upped your game,
then you could get inside
Hood's secret camp and...
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
...who knows what you might find there?
- Now, with a little tuition from me...
- Hey, we rob fools for a living.
Oh, so do I. So do I.
How does, um...
Robin Hood's secret treasure interest you?
Yeah? And your cut's the lion's share?
No, no, no. I don't want any of it.
You can have it all. Have it all.
I'm only interested in a teeny-weeny
bit of paper that belongs to me.
- Who are you?
- I am the man with the plan.
So, shall we begin the lesson?
Search the houses, one each.
They are looking everywhere. They're even
dredging ponds. He's just nowhere.
- Keep searching.
- Right.
Ah, it's good, this,
you and me, back on a mission.
I mean, no offence against the others, but...
it's like the good old days,
back in the Holy Land.
Look.
These shoes, they were definitely made
by the Sheriff's smithy, weren't they?
Yeah.
- That's him.
- Come on.
Master, you know that ring,
the one Marian gave you?
- Is it a new code?
- No.
- I gave it to her when we were in the tree.
- Ha-ha!
What, you giving jewelry?
That must have surprised her.
She probably thought
you were going to propose.
Yeah, I did.
And she said yes.
Well, this is when
you're supposed to say, "Congratula... "
Congratulations!
- She said yes?
- She did.
That's incredible.
Only if we live to enjoy it.
Come on.
He went this way, come on.
It's not enough just to be...
...poor and dirty.
I could do old.
- Works every time with the nuns.
- Yes, yes. Not bad, but you see, come here.
You really need something
that makes you stand out,
really stand out from the poor crowd.
- We could be sick as well.
- Better, better.
We can do foaming at the mouth.
- Oh, and deathly pallor.
- Oh!
Oh, yes. Yes, the poor distraught mother
desperately trying to protect her dying brood.
Excellent, excellent! Eat the lot.
But you see, not just old and weak.
But... Ah! Blind!
He's blind an' all!
Ah... Thank you very much. You're too kind.
But what we need is a clincher.
Now, what would make Robin Hood's
bleeding heart really gush?
For a big enough haul, I could
always chop one of the kid's arms off.
Ah-ha-ha. I like your thinking.
Very good, but, er... no.
I have a better idea.
- It's not enough.
- That's all there is.
- There's not enough to feed the villagers.
- We'll feed families with children first.
- No, we need more food.
- No. We need to find the Sheriff.
- I don't care about the Sheriff.
- All right.
- Then you don't care about Nottingham.
- That's not what I meant.
John, if the Sheriff isn't found,
Nottingham will be destroyed.
Everyone... Everyone else
is out looking for the Sheriff.
Yes, and that's what we should be doing too.
I can't let people starve.
- And I won't go against Robin's orders.
- Why?
Because he's right.
And he's our leader.
Leaders can be wrong.
Sir Jasper,
I think that we can come
to some sort of understanding.
I know you're only acting in the
Sheriff's best interests and so are we.
You're not doing a very good job of it.
The truth is that we just don't know
where he is, and we need more time.
Look, rules are rules.
If I make an exception, the next thing, every
ambitious captain is murdering his Sheriff
thinking he can get away with it.
- I've not murdered him. I can assure you.
- Well...
I could make you a very rich man.
Look, if Nottingham or Derby or any
other town under Prince John's protection
gets razed to the ground,
it has to be rebuilt,
and it so happens
that the Royal Charter for Reconstruction
has been licensed to my cousin.
Did you think I was going to be
a glorified messenger all my life?
- You really are going to do this.
- Oh, yes.
Come sunset, no Sheriff, no Nottingham.
It always amazes me
how much dust an army kicks up.
But then it's a very big army.
- Three more drops.
- Yes, one here and two more before the river.
Someone must have seen the Sheriff by now.
Oh, my baby!
- Dear God.
- Oh, my baby!
Oh, my baby!
No-one.
No-one should be reduced to this.
By the looks of them,
that is not the last grave they'll dig.
Not if I can help it.
Oh, my baby!
Do not be alarmed, no-one will hurt you.
- We're with Robin Hood.
- Oh, God bless you.
God bless you.
Why didn't you take me
instead of my only grandchild?
We must stay here and help them.
- John, we have a mission.
- They are our mission.
- Robin has asked us...
- Robin is not here! We are.
These people need our help.
- Jasper will not be swayed.
- There's still time.
- There's still time for you to get away.
- No.
You did not run
when I was being held hostage.
I'm not leaving you in trouble.
Well, then...
we must prepare to defend ourselves.
Search all of the villages.
Just find him. Go. Ask around.
I don't think we're going
to get out of this, Will.
But if we do, do you...
Do you reckon I could come back to the lads?
- Too late, Allan. Miles too late.
- Come on!
- I made a few mistakes...
- Mistakes? You deliberately betrayed us!
- Strictly speaking, that's true.
- Yeah.
Yeah. But it's not that
simple, Will, all right?
I never told Gisborne where the camp is.
I saved your life, didn't I?
Well? I know a lot
about how this place works now.
That's gonna help Robin, right?
Come on, what do you reckon?
The old team back together?
You're with Gisborne now.
There's no coming back from there.
I'm getting used to it,
life as an heroic outlaw.
The King will come back,
you and Marian will be married,
living in some grand old mansion...
Well, well, well.
Look at these marks.
They carry on this way. Come on.
- I mean, it's all going to end.
- Tell it to the sun, Much!
Look, it's racing across the sky
and if we don't find the Sheriff
before sundown, everything will end.
Me, you, Marian, everything!
There'll be nothing left but scorched earth.
Oh! So cold...
- So cold.
- I've got some medicines back at camp.
No.
- We take them with us.
- The camp is secret.
Look at them!
Do you think it's a good idea
to leave them out here? Truthfully?
The old man won't know.
The rest we blindfold.
- Can I just have a word?
- I assume you're talking to me.
- Sorry, Sir Jasper. If you've got a moment.
- Go on.
Between you and me,
Guy is not very good at talking himself up.
I want you to know
we're doing everything we can here.
Good.
There's not a long of men
that would do what Guy's doing right now.
You should keep him in mind for other
things. He could be useful in another county.
What? Him and you?
Well, yeah, I suppose so.
It's interesting, isn't it, when people
realize that they're going to die?
Suddenly all this new-found loyalty
creeps out of the woodwork.
- Well, I want to live.
- Allan...
- You'd better find the Sheriff then.
- I thought I gave you a job to do.
You did. I'm on it.
- Your boy wants to save you.
- This isn't about me.
This is about the people of Nottingham.
Correct, and much as I dislike you,
you need not fear the onslaught.
As a Black Knight, you and your family
may pass freely through the town.
- I have no family.
- Good. Keeps things simple.
But I do have friends.
- Family, not friends.
- One person in particular.
- Oh, a particular Lady Marian?
- Yes.
We were engaged
and I have reason to hope that...
Wait, wait, wait. "Reason to hope"?
Doesn't really wash.
- In time, she will be family.
- In time?
- Yes. In time she will be my wife.
- Not if she's dead.
- Marian comes with me.
- Yes.
If you've married her by then.
I can't marry her
between now and sunset, can I?
Why not? She's hardly
going to say no, is she?
Sir Jasper! Sir Jasper!
The time for talking is over.
I have to brief my troops.
- Well, at least let us evacuate the town!
- No.
- The women and children, spare them...
- An example has to be set.
As Prince John always says,
the best examples are written in blood.
- How many?
- They're surrounding the town.
It's going to take a lot to do that.
Get all of our guards into siege positions.
What guards?
They're all out looking for the Sheriff.
- Get every able-bodied man into the armory.
- You trust this lot with weapons?
We're fighting for our lives now, all of us.
- Hang on...
- Just do it!
All right.
Nearly there.
Try to get some rest.
We'll bring food and medicine.
The promised land.
Oh... Oh!
- Help me...
- I'm coming.
- This way, I'm here now.
- Help me.
- Straight on. Straight on.
- A little bit of cheese.
- Yeah. We'll give you a little wash first.
- Oh. So tired.
- Where's Marian?
- Will.
- It looks like we're brothers in arms again.
- Ha-ha! Not exactly what I had in mind.
Will! Any word from Robin?
But I know he will die
before he stops looking.
- Today that's not good enough, Will.
- Marian...
The one person who can't die is you.
- There's no way out.
- I promised Robin you'd be safe.
Where is he going?
You know, I was thinking, I might stay here
when you and Marian are, you know...
Much, look.
I think we're gaining on him.
These are fresh footprints.
Or I could be a lone outlaw.
The Sherwood Avenger...
Much, come here.
Yes!
Only one man in Nottingham
has nightclothes like that. Oi!
I don't believe it!
- Where did you get those clothes?
- I traded them, fair and square, for good rags.
You traded rags for silk pajamas?
I don't think so.
It's true.
A little man. Ugly.
Said my rags would help him find
important papers in the forest.
Papers?
- That's the pact!
- The pact?
The camp! Come on!
- Marian...
- Has he changed his mind?
No, but I've managed
to negotiate a concession.
Nottingham cannot be spared,
but he will spare me and my family.
- You're abandoning us?
- I've no intention of abandoning you, Marian.
You could become my family
and we could leave together if...
...you marry me.
Is it such a difficult choice,
between death and being my wife?
It's not that simple.
How can I abandon them?
Marry me... and live.
It has to be before sunset.
That's when I leave.
Argh!
Come on.
I'm slowing you down.
- Go! Don't worry about me.
- Hey, Much. I like worrying about you.
Now come on. Come on!
I won't be long.
We have numbers, so don't bunch up,
and make sure you use the little brats.
Heroes aren't allowed to kill kids.
- There's no other way.
- There has to be!
Marian, there is a ring of steel
around Nottingham.
- If we got beyond the walls, we'd be cut down.
- Then we will have to fight as best we can.
Marian, you can't save these...
You can't save these people.
Look, much as I hate Gisborne,
you have to marry him.
- No!
- Wherever you go... Wherever you go,
Robin will move heaven and earth,
he will find you.
Just stay alive.
Robin! This doesn't make any sense!
- There's no way the Sheriff will find our camp.
- He knows, Much.
- Somehow he knows.
- What if you're wrong?
Look at the sun!
We're nearly out of time!
We should go to Nottingham,
rescue Marian and Will and whoever we can.
No, Much!
The Sheriff is heading for the camp, and
finding him is the only way to save anyone!
Actually, we won't be staying for lunch.
I know you.
- I helped you!
- Yeah, thanks for that. Where's the loot?
- Stop!
- Get your hands off my children!
Good. Right, you tie up the oaf.
- I'll go find the stash.
- Er... we'll find the stash.
Boys, tie up the big man.
Ha-ha!
Yes, well, he does give to the poor.
There! There! There!
Come on, Hood.
It's here somewhere.
Ah!
Yes!
Ha-ha-ha!
- Come to mamma!
- Don't slobber over it, woman!
Don't! You stupid old man!
In one day,
I've been a rich man, a poor man,
a beggar man, and now a thief!
Traitors!
Yes, and so young!
Hood!
Please! Please! Don't shoot!
Think of the children.
Out of my kitchen!
You really need to work
on your parenting skills.
And you... You shouldn't be out so late.
Back up!
You can't touch me, Hood.
Not unless you want your beloved,
stinking, poor whingeing paupers to burn!
- Nobody's burning anything.
- You have to get me to Nottingham by sunset.
And there's nothing you can do about it.
Confused, he will be.
Marian, we're out of time.
What's your decision?
I'm not going to walk out on these people.
- So you're going to stay?
- Yes.
Woman!
Your willfulness will kill you.
Oh, it's getting cold.
Shall we light a fire?
Get those gates open!
And the woman, Marian?
Is she leaving with you?
She will not abandon Nottingham.
Imbecile.
And without her,
my world may as well turn to ash.
Marian!
- You came back!
- If I'm going to die, I'll die by your side.
To arms!
They're coming! They're coming!
Marry me now,
and make it the last thing we do.
Let's steal that from them, at least.
Gisborne!
- You're alive!
- Don't you just stand there!
Give me that damned seal!
One day!
I'm away for one day,
and look at it!
Huh? Look at it!
- Are you still here?
- No, my lord.
You heard him, stand down!
My lord, what happened?
Where did you go?
I just thought I'd see
how you'd cope without me for a day.
- Hood found you.
- And?
- He could still be here, we could still get him.
- No. No, I don't need him any more.
Single-handedly...
I, single-handedly, managed to infiltrate
Hood's secret camp and retrieve the pact.
Ha-ha! The pact! Ha-ha!
The pact! The pact! No...
The pact! The pact! Get him! Get after him!
Well, that's the paperwork done.
Yeah.
It's my fault we nearly lost that thing.
If the Sheriff finds this camp again,
I will never forgive myself.
I've been a fool, Robin.
I'm sorry I disobeyed your orders.
You're a good man, John,
who cares about his fellow men.
Never, ever apologize for that.
Robin, do you really think
the Sheriff was sleepwalking?
Nothing that man does would surprise me.
I'm sorry.
No, no-one can ride a horse in their sleep.
Ah! I knew a man once who got up,
milked all his goats and then went
right back to bed, all in his sleep.
- What?
- It's true! His wife saw it.
- Didn't she wake him up?
- Are you mad?
She went out and bought six more goats!